

asknanishankar@gmail.com



+91-8329150928



Mumbai, India



shankar24397.github.io/Profile/



linkedin.com/in/shankar-asknani-519756136github.com/shankar2 4397

-

medium.com/@asknanishankar

GENERAL SKILLS

(Configuration &

Agile Methodologies & BI

Shell Scripting

LANGUAGES & TOOLS

- * Python , SQL, Yaml, Shell Scripting
- Full Professional Proficiency
- * Tools AWS, PuTTY, Vim, Anaconda, Power BI, Git, Postman, bitbucket, Jira, jenkins Full Professional Proficiency
- * Achieved Hackerrank Gold Badge in SQL - 2020 Full Professional Proficiency

Shankar Asknani

Software Engineer

Working as Software Engineer with around 5 years of experience in automating usecases using python and configuration management tool ansible & also analyzing data in order to drive successful business solutions. Worked with various infra domain. Proficient knowledge in DevOps. Excellent understanding of operations and automation technologies to integrate and solve complex business problems, looking out for interesting opportunities to apply & grow in DevOps domain.

WORK EXPERIENCE

DevOps Automation Engineer (Consultant) Capgemini

04/2022 - Present Mumbai, India

As a key strategic partner to companies around the world, Capgemini have leveraged technology to enable business transformation for more than 50 years

- Infrastructure Automation Configuration Management: As a part of a project i completed automating 8 key use-cases which saved roughly around €10k saving & 17 days of manual work, Which includes Healthcheck reports, Auto server monitoring & triggering the playbook via a scheduler in ansible tower. Fetched, Filtered Json & identified Monitoring Alerts from API (Dynatrace)triggered via URI ansible module.
- □ Building Custom Ansible Roles & python scripts: Created reusable role & shell wrappers in ansible which extends the Functionality of automation bot. Using Ansible + python for sharing secret information to end user, making sure that security is intact. Also Converting or triggering python scripts to playbooks for faster parallel processing & making it scalable & flexible for larger inventory servers testing.
- □ Tech Stack Used: Python, Ansible, Ansible Tower/AWX, Jinja2, Jenkins, Hashicorp Vault, Gitlab, postman. Client: Credit agricole bank

Software Development Engineer

L&T infotech (LTI)

08/2018 - 04/2021

Achievements/Tasks

Mumbai, India

- □ Project-3: Recent work included NLU Search engine(RASA) and its retraining, improved performance and achieved 74% accurate responses (using avg F1 - Rasa test script) on queries. Tech stack used NLP, Machine learning, Data analysis and Deep learning.
- □ Project-2: Coded MS Operations Connector Bridge for SCOM monitoring tool in python. its a connector bridge between monitoring tool environment and AIOPS platform hosted in different servers.
- □ Project -1: Worked extensively on Data preprocessing & EDA, making data as model ready doing required using python and BI tools.
- □ Tech Stack Used: Python, RASA Framework, Anaconda, Postman, Git.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- * Ansible, Ansible Tower/ AWX, Yaml, Hashicorp Vault
- * Jenkins, Gitlab, Jfrog & NIM (Artifact Repository)
- * Data Preprocessing & Transformation, EDA and visualization using PowerBi & Python
- * Data Structures and Algorithms, Operating Systems, Front End Templating and FLASK API.

CERTIFICATES

Applied Machine Learning in Python (University of Michigen) (01/2020 - Present) Certificate Authentic code: H2D96VN25UG8

Neural Networks and Deep Learning (DeepLearning.ai) (12/2019 - Present) Certificate Authentic code: 4AUXR7UHU349

EDUCATION

Bachelor's in Computer Science & Engineering (B.E) Mumbai Univeristy

04/2014 - 04/2018 Mumbai, IN